Adventure comes out of the blue.
Smurfs is a animation, family, fantasy film directed by Chris Miller.
When Papa Smurf is mysteriously taken by evil wizards, Razamel and Gargamel,
Smurfette leads the Smurfs on a mission into the real world to save him.
With the help of new friends, the Smurfs must discover what
defines their destiny to save the universe.
Smurfette (voice), played by Rihanna.
No Name (voice), played by James Corden.
Ken (voice), played by Nick Offerman.
Gargamel / Razamel (voice), played by JP Karliak.
Joel (voice), played by Dan Levy.
Jaunty (voice), played by Amy Sedaris.
Smurfs is a 2025 American live-action animated musical fantasy comedy film based on
The Smurfs comic book series created by the Belgian comics artist Peyo.
A reboot of The Smurfs film series, the film was directed
by Chris Miller and written by Pam Brady.
It stars Rihanna, who also produces the film, as the voice of Smurfette, alongside an ensemble cast including James Corden, Nick Offerman, JP Karliak, Daniel Levy, Amy
Sedaris, Natasha Lyonne, Sandra Oh, Jimmy Kimmel, Octavia Spencer, Nick Kroll, Hannah Waddingham, Alex Winter, Maya Erskine, Kurt Russell, and John Goodman.
In February 2022, it was reported that Lafig S.A.
and IMPS, now known as Peyo Company, the owners of the Smurfs brand, had agreed to a partnership with Paramount
Animation to produce multiple animated Smurfs films, with the first project being a musical.
Brady was attached to write the screenplay, with
production set to begin later that year.
By June 2022, Miller had been hired to direct the film, and by April 2023, Rihanna had joined the
film as a voice actor and producer, along with writing and recording original songs.
Animation services were provided by Cinesite.
Smurfs premiered in Brussels on June 28, 2025, and was released by
Paramount Pictures in the United States on July 18.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics and, despite grossing over $124.1 million worldwide,
was ultimately considered to be a box-office disappointment and lost $80 million for Paramount.
The film explores themes of musical, portal, based on
comic, shocking, live action and animation.